翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
So to really dig in and make sure we understand the difference between a static and an instance method.
现在我们要深入研究，确保理解 static 和实例方法之间的区别
So what do we know so far?
目前为止我们都知道哪些呢？
Well, we know that there exist static methods,
我们知道静态方法中
which have the word static in their declaration,
声明的位置具有 static 关键词
and non-static methods, also known as instance methods,
非静态（实例）方法
which do not or-- yeah, which don't.
没有 static 关键词
So static methods are invoked using the class name.
另外静态方式使用类名调用
So we know, for example, if we want to call a makeNoise method that was declared like this
所以如果想调用这样声明的 static 方法
we would say Dog, great ethereal sky Dog, I would like you to make a noise.
我会说：“狗狗们，叫出点声音吧”
And so it will.
就是这样
Instant methods, by contrast, are invoked using an instance name.
实例方法由实例名调用
So I might say maya, the dog, please make noise.
我会说：“maya 这只狗，请叫出声音吧”
So I create a specific dog and I say, maya, make your noise.
我创造了一只具体的狗让它叫
And an important distinction between them is that static methods, they cannot access my instance variables.
一个重要区别是静态方法不能访问实例变量
I couldn't say, System.out.print line weightInPounds,
不能写 System.out.println(weightInPounds)
because in this case, there is no me.
因为在这种情况下没有特定的狗
There's just the idea of dogs trying to make the noise.
只有这样才能让狗叫
And over here, it's a specific dog.
这边的是一条特定的狗
So why? What good is a static method?
那静态方法有什么用呢？
It seems like the way I've described it that non-static methods are simply more powerful.
好像非静态方法更强大一些
But we'll see that there is a natural place for a static method.
但静态方法也有存在的意义
So for example, some classes, they're just never instantiated, for example the Math class.
例如像 Math 类从来没有实例化过
The way we'll usually or--
我们通常...
The way we would use the round method of the Math is I would say, mathematics, please round 5.6,
使用 Math 类的 round() 方法时：“数学类，请计算 round(5.6)”
which just makes more sense than saying,
这比下面的说法更有意义
let's create a specific Math, whatever that would mean,
让我们创建一个数学 m
and then use m's round.
然后使用 m 的 round() 方法
So static methods, they have their place that are more natural.
所以静态方法有适合的使用场景
Now, sometimes classes can actually have a mix.
实际上类是可以混合的
You can have a class that is both static and non-static methods.
既拥有静态方法又拥有非静态方法
And what we'll do is we'll build one right here.
我们马上创建一个
But I think it will be more interesting if we jump in live.
要是现场直播会更有意思的
So let's open up our Dog class.
打开 Dog 类
And let's say that our goal is we want to be able to compare two dogs.
假设我们要比较两只狗
So I'm going to make another dog, d2, Dog 100.
需要先创建另一只狗 d2
And I want to compare these dogs,
我想比较一下它们
so I might do something like bigger equals and now I want to say Dog.maxDog d, d2.
所以我需要这样写...
Now the idea here is that I don't want either of the dogs to be doing the judging.
我不想让任何一条狗来评价
I want an expert at dogs.
我需要一位狗方面的专家（狗神）
I'll ask the god version of Dog to do the judgment.
让狗神来判断
And in that case, it's pretty natural.
这是正常的使用方式
So let's try it out.
让我们试一试吧
So in this case, we want to make a method of maxDog.
创建 maxDog() 方法
And it's supposed to take two dogs, d1 and d2.
它需要两只狗 d1 和 d2
And if d1 is bigger than d2, we're going to--
如果 d1 大于 d2，就...
oh, sorry. If d1.weightInPounds is bigger than d2.weightInPounds,
啊对不起，如果 d1.weightInPounds 大于 d2.weightInPounds
we'll return d1.
则返回 d1
Otherwise, we'll return d2.
否则返回 d2
Now, this is not done yet.
现在还没有完成
So what I want you to do is think for a moment, what is missing here, other than this?
想一想还缺少什么？
That's kind of obvious.
很明显
So what's missing?
少了什么呢？
There's two things.
少了两个东西
So one of them is this needs a return type.
一个是返回类型
And the other is static, because in this case, we're invoking the method using the class name.
另一个是static，因为我们要使用类名调用方法
So let's try doing dogLauncher, see if everything works.
试一下 DogLauncher 是否正常
Can we try running it? Probably nothing should-- yeah.
尝试运行一下
Nothing happens.
没有报错
So we'll make the bigger dog make a sound.
让大一些的狗叫
And let's change the numbers so we actually know what's going on, so 15 and 100.
为了更好的观察，我们把数字改成15和100
So in this case, if it's working properly we should get a woof.
这样如果正常的话我们会得到 woof
And indeed we get a woof.
也确实得到了 woof
So you might ask yourself, couldn't I also make a not-static version, like public Dog maxDog Dog d2?
实现非静态版本可以吗？比如说 public Dog maxDog(Dog d2)
And then I could compare my own self.
这样可以跟自己比较
And yes, you could.
确实可以
You could say in this case, if my weightIn Pounds is greater than d2's weightInPounds, then return--
如果我的 weightInPounds 大于 d2 的 weightInPounds
and in this particular instance, I want to return a reference to my own self,
在这个特殊的例子中，我要返回自己的引用
so we'll use that keyword that I very briefly alluded to earlier and say return this.
因此使用之前简单提过的关键字 return this
Otherwise, we'll return d2.
否则返回 d2
Now for clarity, you can also add this so that a reader of your code might say,
你还可以添加 this 让代码更清晰，阅读代码的人会说
OK, it's my weightInPounds, because this is a non-static method, so a specific dog is going to do the judging.
这是一个非静态方法，由一只具体的狗判断 weightInPounds 属性
And an exercise you might do now is try and ponder,
你可以思考一下
how would I call that method?
如何调用该方法呢？
So what would the call look like?
该怎样调用呢？
It might look like this.
应该是这样
And so in that case, this dog does the judging to see,
这种情况下 d 这只狗来做判断
am I bigger than this other dog?
“我比另一只狗大吗？”
And it decides no, and so this method will return the larger dog.
答案是不，所以返回较大的那只狗
So it's up to you?
你觉得哪种好？
Like, do you feel comfortable having dogs judge themselves against other dogs?
让狗自己进行判断更舒服一点吗？
Or would you rather have an impartial judge that will just feel more aesthetically correct to you?
或者你更愿意设立一个公正的法官？
Either approach is fine.
哪种方法都可以
Either will work perfectly.
这两种都很好
It's just a matter of your dog-related moral aesthetics.
只是与你自身审美有关
So one last thing I want to bring up in terms of static--
最后关于 static 的一件事
we're mostly talking about methods, but just as a quick note, we can actually also make static variables.
刚才主要讨论方法，事实上变量也可以是静态的
So these are interesting because they're properties that apply to all dogs.
静态变量是适用于所有狗的特性
And they all share that variable.
狗狗们共享这个变量
So for example, we might say, all dogs have a so-called-- they have a scientific name.
例如所有狗都有一个学名
It should be Canis familiaris, assuming my spelling and capitalization is right.
如果没拼错，应该是 Canis Familaris
And so what that will do is it will establish that all dogs have the same scientific name.
这是所有狗的学名
And so if I run this, I should hopefully get Canis familiaris.
运行后希望得到 Canis Familaris
If I print out the other dog, I get Canis familiaris.
打印另一只狗也会得到 Canis Familaris
Though I would argue that both of these are bad style,
这两种写法都不太好
and that if you're ever accessing a static variable,
如果要访问静态变量
you should really probably only be using,
你真的应该只使用
I mean, in any case I can think of, the actual class.
真正的类名
So instead of saying, hey, maya the dog, what's your scientific name,
也就是不要说：“maya，你的学名是什么？”
I'll say what is the scientific name for all dogs?
应该说：“所有狗的学名是什么？”
So while this syntax works, I don't think it's ever really useful.
因此虽然之前这种语法正确，但极少使用
And it's probably just confusing and might lead you to do bad things.
它会让人困惑，也会造成错误
So what I'm going to say is if you ever have a static variable,
所以如果有一个静态变量
let's use the class name as a nice straightforward way of making sure we know exactly what we're dealing with.
请使用类名明确正在处理的是什么
So if we look again at this method,
再看一下这个方法
this is what we've just built. But I think it's a little more interesting in this bigger context.
这是我们刚刚创建的，放在更大的上下文中讲讲
And so I'll note that a class may have a mix of static and non-static members.
一个类可以有静态成员和非静态成员
And a member is either an instance variable or a method.
成员可以是实例变量，也可以是方法
So a static member, you should access it using the class name.
静态成员应该使用类名来访问
So if I'm saying, what is a dog's scientific name,
所以想知道狗的学名是什么时
I would use this notation.
我会用这个符号
If I want to call the static version of maxDog,
如果我想调用 maxDog 的静态版本
I would use dog.maxDog.
我会用 Dog.maxDog()
You can use an instance variable.
也可以使用实例变量
But again, I think it's confusing,
不过它会令人困惑
so I would say that static members, you really, really should strive to use dog.
所以静态成员真的真的应该用 Dog
What I mean by that is, yes, this technically works,
那种方法技术上可行
but please do this.
但这样做更好
It'll just make our lives easier, well, your life easier.
它会避免不少麻烦
Non-static members, by contrast, you cannot invoke them using the class name.
相比之下，非静态成员不能使用类名调用
You cannot say, great sky dog, please make noise if the method is declared as follows.
你不能说：“狗狗们请按照方法声明的那样叫出来吧”
Like if I have here in Dog, I can't call dog.maxDog.
比如这里的方法，我不能调用 Dog.maxDog()
It will say, cannot call non-static method from static--
会报错“不能从静态上下文中调用非静态方法...”
no. Actually, what will it say?
看看实际上会报什么错?
I don't know. Let's find out.
我不知道，一起看看
What happens if we delete this method,
删掉这个方法会发生什么
do dogLauncher, and then say-- yeah, OK.
执行 DogLauncher 然后...
In this case, maxDog, it gets confused.
在本例中，maxDog 会混淆
It gives us an error message that's not particularly useful.
这条报错信息不是很有用
Sorry. A little bit of a digression.
抱歉有点跑题了
But non-static members, if you only have a non-static version of a method, you cannot use the class name to make noise.
非静态成员不能使用类名调用
It just doesn't make sense.
那样是无效的
It's just not what a static method is.
这不是静态方法
And lastly, if you have a static method and you want to access some kind of instance variables--
最后，如果静态方法想访问实例变量
so for example, this method here, maxDog,
比如这里的 maxDog 方法
if we wanted to actually access an instance variable,
如果我们想要访问实例变量
we have to specify which instance.
我们必须指定是哪个实例
We can't take this away, because if we do,
不能删掉它，因为删掉后
we're asking about my instance variables.
意思是访问我自己的实例变量
But the great sky dog, he does not have a weight in pounds.
但是狗这个概念没有 weightInPounds 属性
He transcends petty things like particular sizes.
它不包括这些琐碎的东西
So at this point, if you're new to static versus non-static,
这点对于静态和非静态的新手来说
it's probably a little confusing.
有点让人困惑
I mean, that's just how these programming things go.
这种编程方式
You probably have questions that I haven't answered,
可能会让你产生我没讲到的其他问题
so I encourage you to try out the code link that's on the website, experiment with the code.
因此我鼓励你去链接地址中实验下代码
But especially Project 0 will give you a chance to really deeply look into this issue
特别是项目0，会带你深入思考这个问题
and see how static, non-static, and all of this plays together.
静态、非静态，这些东西是如何一起工作的
翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）